Swapnil Tukaram Shinagare

QA Analyst

Infobelt India Pvt. Ltd. Hyderabad

Cell: 9561251874

Email: swapnilshinagare1@gmail.com

### □ Objective

An experienced Professional having more than 4.5+ years of experience in Functional Testing, Sanity Testing, Regression Testing, Re-Testing, Compatibility Testing, Globalization Testing, Database Testing using Oracle, Automation Testing (Selenium Webdriver using JAVA), API testing using POSTMAN, Git and GitHub version control system wants to be associated with a progressive organization that can provide me with a dynamic work sphere, challenging assignments with responsibility which encourages creativity and keeps in touch with the latest technologies/ trends in the software testing field and have desire and inclination for learning new technologies, a strong work ethic combined with a commitment to excellence in all projects undertaken.

## Experience

Currently working as QA Analyst at Infobelt India Pvt. Ltd. Hyderabad. From June 2022 to April 2023 Domain: Data Compliance Management, Telecom, Investment Banking

Sr. No	Organization & Place	Designation	Duration
1	Gateway corps India Pvt. Ltd. Pune	Software Test Engineer	Jan 2019– July 2022
2	Infobelt India Pvt. Ltd. Hyderabad	QA Analyst	July 2022– April 2023

#### ☐ Technical Skill Set

**Automaton Testing Tools** : Selenium WebDriver with JAVA

**RDBMS** : Oracle 11g **Defect Management Tool** : JIRA Languages : JAVA, SQL **Operating Systems** : Windows, UNIX **API Testing Tool** : POSTMAN

DevOps Tool : Azure, Jenkins

# ☐ Automation Testing Skill Set

- Good understanding of Core Java, OOPs concept, String class, Array, and Collections. □
- Performed Automation testing using Selenium on Web based (Browser) application.
- Proficient in Test Automation using Selenium Tool.
- Good Knowledge in various Frameworks like Data Driven Frameworks.
- Good experience in creating, modifying, and enhancing both manual Test cases and Test Scripts created in Selenium Web Driver.
- Strong exposure to tools like TestNG Framework, build automation tool like Maven.
- Experience in developing the scripts using TestNG annotations.
- Execution of Test Cases with the help of Automation Tool Selenium Webdriver.

•	Experience in working on Page Object Model Design pattern with Hybrid framework.   Good at identifying business components and designing the same.
•	Executed test scripts on Edge, Firefox and Google chrome.  Able to run the test cases for all browser namely Edge, Chrome and Firefox.  Experience in Build Management Tool which is Maven for the Data Driven Framework.  Created Generic and Web Driver Generic classes function for the entire Project.  Good understanding of Automation life cycle and Quality process.  Experience in developing, executing, and maintaining Agile test plans, specifications, test cases, test reports, and documentation.
	Manual Testing Skill Set
•	Strong knowledge of the whole Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) and Software Test Life Cycle (STLC).  Worked in AGILE methodology.  Actively participated in Scrum Meetings to discuss project progress reports every day.  Performed Functional, Integration and Retesting, Regression, Sanity, Browser Compatibility, and Database testing.  Responsible for Test Case Writing, Execution, Bug Tracking, and Reporting.  Actively involved in Review of test Case.  Mapped the business requirements with test case by preparing Traceability matrix.  Work closely with other testers and developers with bug fixes and Defect Analysis using defect management tool such as Jira.  Good in Defect Life Cycle and test plan.  Written SQL queries to access the data from the database tables to ensure data integrity.  Performed API Testing using POSTMAN tool.  A result-oriented team player and skillful in coordinating with the development team and problem-solving abilities.  Capable of working under time constraints in a target-oriented environment.  Self-motivated, Proactive, and Quick learner of new concepts and technologies.  Good experience in Software Testing and Quality Assurance in the Data Compliance Management, Banking domain and Telecom (BSS) Domain.
	Qualifications:
•	Bachelor of Engineering (BE) from Savitribai Phule Pune University, Pune. (Pass out Year-2017)
	Projects
	oject 1 : CRM — Billing and CRM system( Duration- 8 months) ient : Azzurri Communications, UK Project Description:
Bil	lling with roaming partner's area are collected and rated by that roaming partner and finally they are sent to e actual service provider of the roaming customer. Actual service provider charges the end customer for all

the roaming services provided based on their predefined service charges. The Home Public Mobile Network is the network from the operator by which a mobile subscriber has a subscription. The term is used as opposed to Visited Public Mobile Network (VPMN). The Visited Public Mobile Network is the network used by a mobile subscriber while roaming. The term is used as opposed to Home Public Mobile Network (HPMN). Roaming is the ability for a customer of mobile communications to automatically make and receive telephone calls, send and receive data, or access other services while travelling outside the geographical coverage area of the home network, by means of using a network of another operator.

Requirement Analysis: Analyzing the requirements and communicating with the PO team for a better understanding of the requirements. □
Identified End to End Test Scenarios, Test Cases, and Test Data. □
Writing effective and optimized Test Cases in JIRA using Black Box Testing techniques. □
Execution of test cases from Test Lab in JIRA. □
Performing Functional Testing, Regression Testing. □
Validation of Expected output vs. Actual Output in respective logs files. □
Validation of defects, registering them in JIRA, and reporting them to the lead. □

Project 2 : Informa Markets

Client : Informa, UK

Duration : 2 years 10 months Description:

Project's aim is to generate consistent sustainable value for shareholders and maintain positive, long-term relationships with customers, suppliers and our communities. Project offers the corporate, financial and sponsor clients with expert advice, innovative solutions and outstanding execution for both simple and complex transactions and everything in between. Financial capital and infrastructure to deliver products, services and outcomes that customer's value. Equity capital rising, related derivative products, risk management Solutions, IPOs, right issues, follow-on's, block trades, equity-linked transactions and other strategic equity solutions. Debt capital markets: Debt capital rising including investment-grade and emerging market bonds, high-yield bonds, subordinated debt and hybrid capital. Leverage capital markets: Event-driven loans, bonds and mezzanine financing.

#### Role / Job Responsibilities:

•	Analyzing & validating the completeness of business requirements. □
•	Generating the Test scenarios and Test cases. □
•	Generating Regression Test scripts by extracting the requirements that need to be tested from available
	documentation.
•	Developed Automation Test Scripts. □
•	Creating POM (page object model) and Test classes for the framework. □

- Retesting defect fixes on each release build. □
  Performed Sanity, Functional, System Integration, Retesting, Regression testing. □
- Experience in Designing and implementing of TestNG framework with Webdriver.

Project 3 : OAM (OMNI Archive Manager) Organization : Infobelt India Private Limited Domain : Data Compliance Management Duration : 10 months Project Description :  OAM archives, verifies, compresses, encrypts, indexes, and extracts structured and unstructured data from an organization to provide a full data management system for regulatory compliance. OAM provides search capability, query engine, and workflow interfaces. OAM is built for data archiving and data management for the purpose of helping companies become and remain compliant.  Roles /Job Responsibilities:  • Analyzing & validating the completeness of business requirements. □ • Involved in discussions with POs of the project about requirement gaps in the system. □ • Preparing high level test scenarios and passing the team to prepare details test cases. □ • Preparing test data for different databases like Oracle, MS SQL, MySQL, Salesforce, SharePoint, DB2 Google cloud, Amazon S3 and local files. □ • Setting up large test data for the team for their tasks. □ • Responsible for attending and daily standups, sprint planning and sprit retrospectives. □  □ Personal Information  □ Name : Swapnil Tukaram Shinagare   Marital Status : Married   Date of Birth : 24th June, 1994 • Languages Known : English, Hindi ,Marathi • Current Address : Flat. No C702 Anshul kosmos, Near vaishali sweets, Moshi, Pune 412105.  I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.  Place: Pune   Name of Candidate   Name of Candidate   Name of Candidate   Swapnil Tukaram Shinagare)	<ul><li>Conduct Into</li><li>Participated with the ons</li><li>Propose imp</li></ul>	arameterization to implement Data Driven framework.   ernal Test Case Peer Reviews.   in weekly status meetings with the team, developers to discuss open issues and communicate ite team.   rovements to current practices ensuring that approved enhancements are fully implemented at errors are eliminated.
an organization to provide a full data management system for regulatory compliance. OAM provides search capability, query engine, and workflow interfaces. OAM is built for data archiving and data management for the purpose of helping companies become and remain compliant.  Roles /Job Responsibilities:  • Analyzing & validating the completeness of business requirements. □  • Involved in discussions with POs of the project about requirement gaps in the system. □  • Preparing high level test scenarios and passing the team to prepare details test cases. □  • Preparing test data for different databases like Oracle, MS SQL, MySQL, Salesforce, SharePoint, DB2 Google cloud, Amazon S3 and local files. □  • Setting up large test data for the team for their tasks. □  • Responsible for attending and daily standups, sprint planning and sprit retrospectives. □  □ Personal Information  □ Name : Swapnil Tukaram Shinagare □ Marital Status : Married □ Date of Birth : 24th June, 1994  • Languages Known : English, Hindi ,Marathi  • Current Address : Flat. No C702 Anshul kosmos, Near vaishali sweets, Moshi, Pune 412105.  I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.	Organization : I Domain Duration :	nfobelt India Private Limited Data Compliance Management
<ul> <li>Analyzing &amp; validating the completeness of business requirements. □</li> <li>Involved in discussions with POs of the project about requirement gaps in the system. □</li> <li>Preparing high level test scenarios and passing the team to prepare details test cases. □</li> <li>Preparing test data for different databases like Oracle, MS SQL, MySQL, Salesforce, SharePoint, DB2 Google cloud, Amazon S3 and local files. □</li> <li>Setting up large test data for the team for their tasks. □</li> <li>Responsible for attending and daily standups, sprint planning and sprit retrospectives. □</li> <li>Personal Information</li> <li>Name : Swapnil Tukaram Shinagare □ Marital Status : Married □ Date of Birth : 24th June, 1994</li> <li>Languages Known: English, Hindi ,Marathi</li> <li>Current Address : Flat. No C702 Anshul kosmos, Near vaishali sweets, Moshi, Pune 412105.</li> <li>I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.</li> <li>Place: Pune Name of Candidate</li> </ul>	an organization search capability	to provide a full data management system for regulatory compliance. OAM provides y, query engine, and workflow interfaces. OAM is built for data archiving and data
<ul> <li>Involved in discussions with POs of the project about requirement gaps in the system. □</li> <li>Preparing high level test scenarios and passing the team to prepare details test cases. □</li> <li>Preparing test data for different databases like Oracle, MS SQL, MySQL, Salesforce, SharePoint, DB2 Google cloud, Amazon S3 and local files. □</li> <li>Setting up large test data for the team for their tasks. □</li> <li>Responsible for attending and daily standups, sprint planning and sprit retrospectives. □</li> <li>Personal Information</li> <li>Name : Swapnil Tukaram Shinagare □ Marital Status : Married □ Date of Birth : 24<sup>th</sup> June, 1994</li> <li>Languages Known : English, Hindi ,Marathi</li> <li>Current Address : Flat. No C702 Anshul kosmos, Near vaishali sweets, Moshi, Pune 412105.</li> <li>I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.</li> <li>Place: Pune</li> </ul>	Roles /Job Resp	onsibilities:
<ul> <li>Name : Swapnil Tukaram Shinagare</li> <li>Marital Status : Married</li> <li>Date of Birth : 24<sup>th</sup> June, 1994</li> <li>Languages Known : English, Hindi ,Marathi</li> <li>Current Address : Flat. No C702 Anshul kosmos, Near vaishali sweets, Moshi, Pune 412105.</li> <li>I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.</li> <li>Place: Pune Name of Candidate</li> </ul>	<ul><li>Involved in</li><li>Preparing hi</li><li>Preparing te Google clou</li><li>Setting up la</li></ul>	discussions with POs of the project about requirement gaps in the system.   gh level test scenarios and passing the team to prepare details test cases.   st data for different databases like Oracle, MS SQL, MySQL, Salesforce, SharePoint, DB2, d, Amazon S3 and local files.   gree test data for the team for their tasks.
<ul> <li>□ Marital Status : Married</li> <li>□ Date of Birth : 24<sup>th</sup> June, 1994</li> <li>Languages Known : English, Hindi ,Marathi</li> <li>Current Address : Flat. No C702 Anshul kosmos, Near vaishali sweets, Moshi, Pune 412105.</li> <li>I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.</li> <li>Place: Pune Name of Candidate</li> </ul>	☐ Personal Inf	ormation
	<ul><li>☐ Marital :</li><li>☐ Date of :</li><li>Languages I</li><li>Current Add</li></ul>	Status: Married Birth: 24 <sup>th</sup> June, 1994 Known: English, Hindi, Marathi ress: Flat. No C702 Anshul kosmos, Near vaishali sweets, Moshi, Pune 412105.